DANIEL ARCÉ

Front-End Development

daniel.arce@gmail.com (646)506-8957 Brooklyn, NY

SUMMARY

I am an experienced front-end developer with a passion for accessibility and a multidisciplinary education, including a deep understanding of interaction design. I have over twelve years of experience as a web developer and more than four years of experience creating web applications. The ability to communicate technical concepts to a non-technical audience has led me toward teams researching and creating working prototypes of new features.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Web Developer Apr 2023 — present

- Extracted assets from a legacy Flash website, redesigned and developed barbarabeirne.com, a photo portfolio site (2023).
- Rebranded and developed a new site for bauhausdances.org with a custom-built WordPress theme (2023).

Professional Sabbatical - Personal Growth and Professional Development

Jul 2022 — Mar 2023

- Classical portraiture and life drawing intensive, Grand Central Atelier, New York, Summer 2022
- Full-Stack Web Development, University of Helsinki Certificate, March 2023

Photoshelter - Senior Front-End Developer New York

Sep 2018 — Feb 2022

Photoshelter.com is a Cloud-based Digital Asset Management tool for creative teams, hosting over 1 billion files for 80,000 professionals. Research and Development team - Jan 2021 - Feb 2022

- Prototyped a workflow automation interface. This prototype was the basis of a new feature launched later that year.
- Proposed an experimental image blur detection tool. This working proof-of-concept allowed the company to measure interest in this tool.
- · Participated in cross-team discussions with our Chief Architect that steered the direction of new features and product requirements.
- · Coded new features using PolymerLit, React, and the Javascript implementation of OpenCV.

Production team - Sep 2018 - Jan 2021:

- · Spearheaded the adoption of accessibility coding standards, which proved crucial in maintaining and securing new institutional clients.
- Led the codebase's accessibility standards audit.
- · Implemented keyboard navigation for nested collections, eliminating much of the accessibility tech debt.
- · Contributed to the next version of the app written in React.
- Worked closely with product and UX designers on planning and developing new features.
- · Automated unit tests with Mocha and Chai.
- · Mentored junior developers.

Apple Inc - Senior Front-End Developer (contract) Sunnyvale Campus

Jul 2017 — Mar 2018

- ullet Converted static designs to responsive, pixel-perfect code for the media launch of the $iPhone\ X$.
- · Collaborated with the marketing and design teams to realize projects for Apple.com.
- Prototyped and developed the first direct mail by the Marketing Department using CSS3 animations.
- Authored automation tools for direct mail campaigns using Node.js, bash script, and Gulp.

Creative Technologist, New York, Toronto

2014 - 2017

- Built a texting app with the Twilio SMS API for "Texting Syria," an artistic installation I created in collaboration with photojournalist Liam Maloney.
- Presented this installation at The Nobel Peace Center, Oslo (2017), Photoville in Brooklyn (2016), and Scotiabank's Nuit Blanche, Toronto (2014).

Publicis North America - Senior Interactive Developer New York

Nov 2015 – Nov 2016

Brought citirewards.com up to level AAA of the Web Content Accessibility Guidelines (WCAG)
Worked with designers and product managers to create web campaigns for clients, including Verizon, LG, and Colgate.

Code and Theory - Senior Front-End Developer New York

Mar 2015 - Nov 2015

- · Consulted and collaborated with UX designers and developers to build the motel6.com price management tool in EmberJS.
- Prototyped single-page web applications for Comcast in AngularJS.
- Automated building and deployment tasks for static sites with Gulp and Grunt.

MSNBC - Senior Design Technologist and Front-End Developer New York

Oct 2013 - Mar 2015

- Iterated working prototypes in Javascript during the ideation and design phase for msnbc.com/videos with a cross-disciplinary team.
- Authored Drupal modules in PHP, Javascript/jQuery, and CSS3 for msnbc.com.

Kirshenbaum Bond Senecal - Design Technologist and Front-End Developer New York

Jan 2013 – Oct 2013

- Promoted the use of object-oriented patterns in Javascript. This improved the maintainability of the codebase.
- · Created and maintained static micro-sites for various clients, including Puma, BMW, and Bank of New York Mellon.

The Huffington Post / AOL - UI Engineer New York

May 2011 - Nov 2012

- · Worked with Front-End engineers to optimize the site's loading and rendering times, which resulted in a 30% improvement in loading times.
- Prototyped the new site-wide main navigation using jQuery and Javascript.

EDUCATION

Full-Stack Web Development, University of Helsinki Certificate, March 2023

· React, Redux, and Node.js

NYU Tisch School of the Arts, New York, 2010

Master of Professional Studies, Interactive Telecommunications Program (ITP)

- · Entrance scholarship
- · Studies focused on the intersection of Design and Technology

Concordia University, Montreal

BFA, Interdisciplinary Studies

Focus on digital media production, video, and electro-acoustics